journeymart.com 2015-12-30

# Privacy Policy :: JourneyMart.com

JourneyMart respects the privacy of its users and is committed to protecting it. The information collected is used to enable the portal and JourneyMart Alliance Partners to provide efficient service and to personalize your JourneyMart experience. We would like you to understand the ways in which we do and don’t use this information, and the details of our Privacy Policy are given below.

Information is collected in two ways:   
Supplied by you at Registration  
Supplied by you at the time of querying for a product listed on JourneyMart  
Tracking information gathered routinely as visitors navigate the site  

---  
  
#### Registration

All users are initially requested to submit basic information at the registration stage. We may ask for your name, email address, city and country of residence and we may request for information about your interests in order to personalize the site and make it more useful to you. The more you tell us about yourself, the more value we can offer you.  
Supplying this information is not mandatory at this stage. However, we will be unable to tell you about new developments in your area or region of interests, or answer your queries without this data. You would of course be free to surf and go through the valuable destination content and travel tools without registration.  
The registration information consists of Personal Information as well as non-personal Demographic Information. Your Personal Information, is kept private with JourneyMart We shall not disclose this information unless acting under a good faith belief that such action is necessary to   
1) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process   
2) protect and defend the rights and property of JourneyMart.com   
3) Enforce JourneyMart Terms of Usage and Notices; or   
4) act to protect the interests of its’ members or others 

Non-personally identifiable information is used to provide a more personalized advertising experience, and may entail the use of log files and cookies (see below).

There are certain areas where it will be mandatory for you to register and provide information:

#### Booking and Buying

While booking and buying on the JourneyMart, you will be asked, among other details, for your name, email address, address and financial data, specially credit card details and /or other modes of payment to facilitate the service and transaction.  
Due to the increasing number of internet frauds and to protect both the Card Holder and the Merchant our risk management team reviews every online transaction and we are obligated to request and verify additional information from the card holder. Only on successful verification of the transaction is the same considered paid for. We may request you for additional documentation like scanned copies of your passport, front and back of your card, copy of your visa's / authority letter to authenticate your charge. When sending us the scanned front and back of your credit card please Black out the 3 CVV numbers on the back of your card without which your card cannot be misused.

Further please be advised the information provided by you is kept secure by us and not shared with any third party except when required by the bankers in case of any charge backs or as and when required by the law of the land.  
  
#### Querying for products listed on JourneyMart

At the time of querying for a product we ask you for personal information such as your email, name, city of residence, no. of passengers and any personalised messaging you might want to add along with your request for a holiday. Since this query will be serviced by another Travel Service Provider i.e. Travel Agent, Hotel, Cruise Company etc JourneyMart will share this information voluntarily supplied by you with the service provider whose product you have chosen so that they can assist you better in understanding and planning your holiday. 

By way of submitting such details such as your name, email, no. of passengers, approximate date of travel, any personalised messaging etc, you as the customer are allowing JourneyMart to share such information with the Travel Service Provider who will service the request.   
  
#### Community areas - Bulletin Board/Online Chat

These are areas where you interact with other users. It is mandatory to register, if you have not done so already, before you use these services. The purpose is to be able to track any contents or exchange of information which may in anyway be harmful or contrary to law. However there is no legal obligation on the Portal to monitor such material /content /information. 

Kindly note that any personal information provided by you during chat sessions /email exchanges and on message /bulletin boards are considered public and are entirely your responsibility. Do be cautious in sharing your personal information in this manner. It is not covered by the JourneyMart Privacy Policy.   
  
#### Your Choice

JourneyMart will not send you any unsolicited information, including newsletters. New users will receive a welcome email explaining the features of the site. At all times you are given the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of receiving information, newsletters or promotional materials from us or our partners. Simply click on the unsubscribe or opt-out buttons or email us at [unsubscribe@JourneyMart.com](mailto:unsubscribe@JourneyMart.com).   
  
#### IP Addresses / Log Files

IP addresses are used by us and our service providers to analyse trends, track users, movement and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.  
  
#### Cookies

JourneyMart.com uses cookies. It helps us build a better site for you. 

What is a cookie ?   
A cookie is a piece of data/ small file stored on the user’s hard drive by the website. The file contains information about the domain, path, lifetime and value of the visiting variable and helps the website to save information for future reference.

Why do websites store a cookie?  
Websites use cookies for the convenience of the user. Setting a cookie on our site enables you to click onto various pages of the site without typing in your password more than once, thereby saving you time while on our site. It also enables the website to monitor your preferences and customize the web page in accordance with your preferences and interests. Websites use cookies to enable efficient online sales/ services and for tracking popular links or demographics. 

What kind of information becomes accessible because of the cookie?  
Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. It does not actually identify you, just the computer from which you usually access the site. Any information that you do not submit on the website cannot be accessed. Even though the cookie is in your hard disk, it is not equipped to access other information /data on your hard disk. Also one site cannot access the cookie of another site.

When does a cookie terminate?  
Once the user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates. You can delete a cookie by setting your browser not to accept cookies. You still get to use our site. The only drawback to this is that you will not be able to take advantage of the personalized features enjoyed by other users. Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies.   
  
#### Sharing Information

JourneyMart.com does not exchange, provide, sell or rent to any third party the information available to it about the users except as stated below. 

Third parties with whom we share information involve service providers who have listed their products on JourneyMart and from whose product you have so voluntarily given such information. The nature of the information supplied will include personally identifiable information i.e. you can be identified through those details. 

While sharing information with our advertisers, it is usually in the form of aggregated statistics on traffic to various pages within our sites. From time to time, we may share information on visitors to our sites with those marketing products and services that we believe might be of interest to you however we do not divulge personal information submitted by our visitors to advertisers.   
  
#### Surveys & Contests

Our web site may request information for contests and surveys. Submission of these informations are entirely voluntary. You have the option to deny submission of these informations. The kind of information asked is to enable contact, to inform winners of the contests. The surveys ask for demographic details (age, post code) for aggregate use. It helps to monitor the use of the website and improve it.  
  
#### Links

This web site contains links for the benefit of the user. These links allow you to access other websites and therefore when you click a link you exit our website and enter another. Please be alerted that JourneyMart.com is not responsible and has no control over the privacy policy of these other websites.

We urge our users to read and understand the privacy policy of other websites they access before submitting any information. It is important that personally identifiable information collected by other web sites are well protected (not shared/ rented or sold to other parties). The privacy statement of JourneyMart.com applies strictly to the information collected by JourneyMart.com.   
  
#### Security of Information

JourneyMart.com uses virtual and physical security restrictions to protect database and systems. All sensitive information like your personal information and transactions are protected both online and offline by JourneyMart.com. The highest level of Internet privacy and protection presently available is ensured by the most updated Security-Socket- Layer technology, so that transactions and information like credit card details remain private. 

Digital certificates have been obtained in order to enable encryption (128 bit) of information. This will ensure that all information provided by you from through your computer to our server is first transformed into a code before it is dispatched through the Internet. Do look for the locked icon at the bottom of the web browser while on a secure page.

Registration information is stored in a secure operating environment. Any information provided to the employees or licensees or alliance partners of JourneyMart.com is restricted to what is absolutely necessary to provide a superior service. All such employees and Licensees are legally bound by the privacy policies adopted by JourneyMart.com.   
  
#### Updating of Personal Information

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter or promotional materials from us or our Licensees, may unsubscribe by clicking on the unsubscribe button on the communication or sending us an email at [unsubscribe@journeymart.com](mailto:unsubscribe@journeymart.com)  
  
#### Notification of Changes

The Internet is constantly evolving and our Privacy Policy is liable to changes. All changes will be posted here and users should check the Privacy Policy from time to time to always be aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will clearly state that in the Privacy Policy. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner.

If you have any queries about our Privacy Policy or feel that this company is not abiding by its posted Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@journeymart.com](mailto:privacy@journeymart.com). Your privacy is our concern.
